<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Here after foloweth the newe pryuyleges and indulge[n]ces graunted by our holy Father the Pope Leo.x. to the house of seynt Thomas of Acres in London</title>
            <author>St. Thomas's Hospital (London, England)</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>
               <date>1517</date>
            </edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 12 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 2 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2012-10">2012-10 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">A04000</idno>
            <idno type="STC">STC 14077C.58</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC S111499</idno>
            <idno type="EEBO-CITATION">99846828</idno>
            <idno type="PROQUEST">99846828</idno>
            <idno type="VID">11820</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>To the extent possible under law, the Text Creation Partnership has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above, according to the terms of the CC0 1.0 Public Domain Dedication (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). This waiver does not extend to any page images or other supplementary files associated with this work, which may be protected by copyright or other license restrictions. Please go to https://www.textcreationpartnership.org/ for more information about the project.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. A04000)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 11820)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books, 1475-1640 ; 149:07)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>Here after foloweth the newe pryuyleges and indulge[n]ces graunted by our holy Father the Pope Leo.x. to the house of seynt Thomas of Acres in London</title>
                  <author>St. Thomas's Hospital (London, England)</author>
                  <author>Catholic Church. aut</author>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>1 sheet ([1] p.)   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>Richard Pynson,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>[London :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1517?]</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Imprint from STC.</note>
                  <note>List of indulgences granted to the confraternity--STC.</note>
                  <note>Formerly STC 15474.</note>
                  <note>Identified as STC 15474 on UMI microfilm.</note>
                  <note>Imperfect: torn through middle, affecting text.</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of the original in the British Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,368 texts created during Phase 1 of the project (2000-2009), initially available only to institutions that contributed to their creation, were released into the public domain on 1 January 2015. The approximately 40,000 texts produced during Phase 2 (2009- ), of which 34,963 had been released as of 2020, originally similarly restricted, were similarly freed from all restrictions on 1 August 2020. As of that date anyone is free to take and use these texts for any purpose (modify them, annotate them, distribute them, etc.). But we do respectfully request that due credit and attribution be given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Keying and markup guidelines are available at the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp"
                       matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)"
                       replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char"
                       matchPattern="(.+)"
                       replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term>Indulgences --  England --  Early works to 1800.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2011-07</date>
            <label>TCP</label>Assigned for keying and markup</change>
         <change>
            <date>2011-07</date>
            <label>Apex CoVantage</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2011-08</date>
            <label>Judith Siefring</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2011-08</date>
            <label>Judith Siefring</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited</change>
         <change>
            <date>2012-05</date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <body>
         <div type="text">
            <pb facs="tcp:11820:1" rendition="simple:additions"/>
            <head>¶ Here after foloweth the newe pryuyleges and Indulge<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>ces graunted by ou<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> ho<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly Father the Pope Leo .x. to the houſe of ſeynt Thomas of Acres in London.</head>
            <p>
               <seg rend="decorInit">F</seg>Irſte that all &amp; euery Cryſten man &amp; woman beynge <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>ruely penytent &amp; co<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>feſſyd whiche yerely ſhall deuoutly vyſyt the ſayd <note place="margin">The ſtacyons of Rome.</note> Hoſpytall on Aſſhe wednyſday / &amp; .ii. dayes immedyatly next folowynge on Shere thurſdaye / &amp; two dayes imediatly nexte enſuynge / Alſo in the feſtes of the tranſlacyon &amp; matterdome of Seynt Thomas the martyr / and in the euyns of the ſame feſtes puttynge to theyr helpynge handes vnto the reparacyon mayntaynynge and payeng of the dettes of the ſayd Hoſpy<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>tall in eyther of the feſtes aboue ſayd / and euyns of the ſame ſhall obtayne and haue as great &amp; lyke pardon and Indulgence with re<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>myſſyon of ſynnes as if they ꝑſonally ſhuld vyſyt the Churche at Rome named Scala celi / and all other churches and holy places of Rome within and without the ſayd Cytie of Rome / In euery daye of Lent &amp; other tymes of the yere when the ſtacyo<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>s of the ſayde Cytie within &amp; without and Indulgence of the ſame are ſolempnyſed / And as if they had done &amp; fulfylled all maner of thynges whi<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>che ought to be fulfylled to obtayne the ſayd Iudulgence at Rome.</p>
            <p>¶ Secondly that all Criſten people maye the ſooner obtayne the ſayde Indulgence and remyſſyons of ſynnes graunted to the for <note place="margin">Power gyuen to the maſter &amp; his depuy to aſ<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>ſygne co<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>feſſou<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>res.</note> ſayd hoſpytall our holy father the Pope aforeſayd hath grau<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>ted that it may be laufull to the ſayd mayſter of the ſayde Hoſpytall for the tyme beynge in the feſtes aboueſayd &amp; euyns of the ſame to aſſygne &amp; depute ſuffycyent Confeſſours ſeculer or reguler or bothe ſeculer &amp; reguler to gyther whiche mayſter if he be a preeſt / &amp; thyſe co<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>feſſours ſo deputed by hym / or elles if he be no preeſt thyſe ſayde confeſſours by hym or by his laufull deputie ſo deputed
/ And choſen as often as ſhalbe neceſſary after they haue dylygently harde y<hi rend="sup">e</hi> Confeſſions of the ſayd deuout People in theſe dayes / Feſtes / and Vigylles aforeſayd euery yere in the ſayd Hoſpytall may affoy<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>le them ones in theyr lyfe of all &amp; euery of theyr ſynnes crymes exceſſys and delictes howe ſo euer greuous &amp; enorme they be / thoughe they be ſuche as are reſerued vnto the ſee of Rome excepte only thoſe whiche ben conteyned in the Bull whiche is red yerely at Ro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>me on ſher thurſday / but in all other caſes not reſerued vnto the ſayd ſee of Rome the foreſayde confeſſours may affoyle an enioyne them holſome penaunce as often as nede ſhall requyre.</p>
            <p>¶ Thyrdely that the ſaid Confeſſours ſoo deputyd as is aforeſaid by the Mayſter of the ſaid Hoſpitall may commute And tourne <note place="margin">Commutacyo<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g> of vowes &amp; rele<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>ſynge of othes plenary remiſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſion <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>nis <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> lyfe. auctorite to ha<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>ue a<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g> Aulter cal<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>lyd altare por<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tatili.</note> all maner of vowes into other dedes of Charyte / the vowe to Iheruſale<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>
/ the vowe vnto ſeynt Peter and Poule of Rome the vowe vnto ſeynt Iames in Co<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>poſtella / &amp; alſo of Relygyon &amp; chaſtyte oonly <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap>cept / alſo the ſayd co<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>feſſours may releas all maner of oth<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>s.</p>
            <p>¶ Alſo fourthly that the ſayd confeſſours may gyue vnto all criſten people beynge truely contryte and confeſſyd vyſytynge y<hi rend="sup">e</hi> ſayd Hoſpytall in tyme aboueſayd plenare &amp; full remyſſyon of all theyr ſynnes ones in theyr lyfe / &amp; in poynt of deth.</p>
            <p>¶ Alſo fyftly that hit ſhalbe laufull vnto the ſayde mayſter that nowe is and for the tyme ſhalbe / and to the Bretherne of the ſayde houſe / and to all other criſten people of eyther kynde / which for the tyme ſhall enter into the brethe<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>hed of Seynt Thomas the mar<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>tyr that they may haue an Aulter called Altare portatile vpon the which with dewe reuerence and honour in places conuenyent and oneſt / ſoo it be withoute preiudyce of any other man / and alſo that / that the qualyte of theyr buſynes dothe inhaunce or fortune the ſayde mayſter and the foreſayde bretherne and ſuſterne may ſynge maſſe / or cauſe to be ſonge before daylyght / ſo that it be done a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>boutes the Day lyght.</p>
            <p>¶ Prouyded alway that the ſayd mayſter and bretherne do not vſe to celebrat maſſe before Day lyghte accuſtomably / but only at certayne tymes and ſcacely for the reuerence of the bleſſyd ſacrament of the Alter.</p>
            <p>¶ The ſyxte graunte is / if it happen any Brother / or ſuſter of the ſayde Fraternyte or Hoſpitall to come to any Churche interdicte <note place="margin">Dyuyne ſeruy<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>ce may be ſayd and the ſacra<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mentes myny<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtred in Tyme <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 span">
                     <desc>〈…〉</desc>
                  </gap>
               </note> by any ordynary auctoryte or power it ſhalbe laufull ſecretly the dores beynge ſhytte to mynyſter ſacramentes and to ſaye and here Maſſes and other dyuyne Seruyces by theym ſelfe if the ſayde Bretherne be preſtes or by any other preſte ſuffycyent ſeculer or re<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>guler by them deputed / and alſo in tyme of ſuche interdiccyon to receyue &amp; mynyſter the holy ſacrament of the aulter with other Sa<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>cramentes ſaue on Eſter daye without preiudyce of any other perſon in preſence of the ſayd Bretherne and Suſters / and in the <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>
               <g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſence of them <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> ſeruauntes and theyr frendes / ſoo that thoſe Bretherne and Suſterne and other ſuche here<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap> 
               <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 span">
                  <desc>〈…〉</desc>
               </gap>
            </p>
            <p>
               <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 span">
                  <desc>〈…〉</desc>
               </gap> to <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 span">
                  <desc>〈…〉</desc>
               </gap> to <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 span">
                  <desc>〈…〉</desc>
               </gap> 
               <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>he ſayd auctorite ſo it be <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 span">
                  <desc>〈…〉</desc>
               </gap> 
               <note place="margin">
                  <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 span">
                     <desc>〈…〉</desc>
                  </gap> may be <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="3 letters">
                     <desc>•••</desc>
                  </gap>y<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed in Tyme of interdiccyon.</note> perpetually may be obſerued and kepte inuyolate / oure ſayde holy Father Pope Leo aboue named <g ref="char:punc">▪</g> hathe n<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap>ed and <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 span">
                  <desc>〈…〉</desc>
               </gap> the moſte reuerent Father in god the Lorde archebyſſhope of caunterbury Primate of Englande. And alſo the reuerende Fade<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>s in god the lordes Byſſhoppes of London and Nor whytche now beynge / and that hereafter ſhalbe perpetually to be protectoures &amp; de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fendours of the ſayd Hoſpytall and of the aboue reherſed Indulgences and pryuyleges lyke as it is more fully conteyned in the let<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ters of his holyneſſe therupon made vnder leed.</p>
            <p>¶ Alſo our holy Father aboueſayd hath confyrmed and ratyfyed all maner of lyberties / Immunytyes &amp; Indulgens grau<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>ted by his <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>deceſſours Popes of Rome vnto the foreſayd hoſpitall Mayſter and bretherne of acon<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g> in London. Whiche pryuyleges / indulge<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>ces and immunytes hereafter dothe folowe.</p>
            <p>¶ Firſte our holy fader Alexander the fourthe of that Name ſomtyme Pope of Rome graciouſly hath releſyd to all cryſten people <note place="margin">The vii. ꝑte of penau<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>ce relea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſed. A co<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>mau<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>dme<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>t to all <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>lates. In the tyme of interdiccyo<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g> dy<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>uyne ſeruyce may be ſayd o<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nes i<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g> the yere.</note> that doeth helpe or releue y<hi rend="sup">•</hi> ſayd place with theyr goodes or almes / or do take fraternyte of the ſayd place &amp; yerely to the ſame ony Be<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>nefyte gyue or pay / the .vii. parte of penaunce enioyned.</p>
            <p>¶ Alſo our holy father Benet the .xii. of y<hi rend="sup">e</hi> name ſomtyme Pope of Rome co<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>mau<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>deth all prelates to ſuffre the ꝑcuratours of y<hi rend="sup">e</hi> ſayd place to pronou<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>ce and frely expowne theyr nedes and Indulgences in theyr ſayde Churche to the Clergie &amp; other co<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>mune people.</p>
            <p>¶ Alſo if the ſayde procuratours come into ony Cyte Caſtell or towne enterdyted ones yerely haue power to open the Churche do<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>rys there ſo that Dyuyne ſeruyce ſolempnely may be ſayd / curſyd people by name put our / and dede bodyes in the Churchyerde to be buryed / And tho that ſhuld do open penau<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>ce that day ſhalbe releſyd &amp; ſpared. Alſo all bretherne &amp; ſuſterne / whiche ſhall gyue to y<hi rend="sup">e</hi> ſayd place certeyne quantyte of theyr goodes &amp; yerely pay to the Brecherns or proctours of the ſayde hous. And in theyr dyenge be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>quech or aſſygne ony goodes to them / may cheſe yerely to them an able and diſcrete Confeſſour whiche may aſſoyle them plenarly of all ſynnes of the whiche they be verrey contryte and confeſſed / except ſuche as be reſeruyd onely to the courte of Rome / whiche be only .vi. caſes co<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>teyned in theſe .ii. verſes. Percutit incendit falſ at violat fluit a<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>nus / perticipat papa ſex ſolis caſibus iſtis. The vn<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>derſtondynge wherof is this. Percutit / that is to ſey he that ſtrykyth a preeſt or a clerke greuouſly. Incendit / he that wilfully &amp; ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rycyouſly ſetteth any Towne / cytie / or houſe on fyer &amp; ther vpon is denouncyd &amp; a curſed. Falſat / he that counterfaytyth the Popes bullys or letters. Violat / he that brekyth any churche &amp; robbyth the ſame &amp; ther vpon is denounced a curſed by his ordynary. Fluit: Annus / he that is acurſed by the Popes legat &amp; ſo ſtondith by the ſpace of one hole yere. Participat / that is to ſey a Clarke commy<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nynge <note place="margin">Facultye to aſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſoyle all Syn<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nes excepte .vi.</note> in dyuyne ſeruyſe wetyngly &amp; wylfully with a man that is accurſed of the Pope hym ſelfe euery man beynge in any of theſe .vi. caſes muſt go to Rome for abſolucyon in all other caſys they may be Aſſoyled by this pryuylege.</p>
            <p>¶ Alſo the ſayd Confeſſoure may diſpence with them of all vowes made the whiche they may not co<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>uenyenely nor profitably kepe excepte onely the vowe of Iheruſalem &amp; the holy croſſe. Alſo eu<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>ry brother ſhall haue his letter or wrytynge of the ſayd Fraternyte &amp; his ſepulture ſhal not be denyed hym what maner deth he dyeth or deceſyth but if he be acurſed by name by y<hi rend="sup">e</hi> ce<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>ſur<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> of holy churche.</p>
            <p>¶ Alſo our holy father Bonyface the .ix. of that name ſomtyme Pope of Rome to all theym repentaunt and ſhryuen that in the Fe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtis <note place="margin">vii. yeres &amp; .vii. lentes in euery pri<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>cipall feeſt.</note> of the Natiuite / and Circumſiſion of our lorde Iheſu criſte / twelfe daye / paſche day / Aſcenſion daye / Corpus x<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>i day / whytſon daye / Natyuyte / Annunciacion / Puryfycacyon / and Aſſumpcion of our Lady / Alſo the natyuyte of ſeynt Iohu<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g> Baptyſte the appo<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>ſtles / Peter and Poule / the Dedicacyon of the ſayde Churche of ſeynt Thomas / alſo the feſtis of his tranſlacyon &amp; paſſyon / or mar<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>tyrdome / all halowen day<g ref="char:punc">▪</g> F<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>rthermore by the vtas of the ſayde Natyuite of criſte / the Epiphanie / Paſche / Aſcencion / Corpus x<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>i wytſondaye the Natyuyte and Aſſumpcion of our Lady / ſeynt Iohn<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g> Baptyſte the appoſtles Peter / &amp; Poule / and by ſyx dayes next after wytſondaye deuoutly vyſyteth <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>erely the ſame place of ſeynt Thomas / aforeſayd in eche of the ſayd feſtyuall dayes .vii. yeres: &amp; .vii. <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>entes<g ref="char:punc">▪</g> 
               <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> eche of the ſayd vtas<g ref="char:punc">▪</g> &amp; .vii. dayes .C. dayes of pardon of penaunce enioyned marcyfully he hath releſyd.</p>
            <p>¶ Alſo our holy father <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> the ſeconde to all very repentaunte and ſhryuen that deuoutly vyſet the houſe and hoſpytall of ſeynte <note place="margin">vii. yeres &amp; .vii. le<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>tes in certay<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ne teweſdaies.</note> thomas of <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 span">
                  <desc>〈…〉</desc>
               </gap> from <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 span">
                  <desc>〈…〉</desc>
               </gap> vnto y<hi rend="sup">e</hi> vtas of Eſter &amp;. <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>iii. dayes nexte before Eſter daye / And alſo euery day within y<hi rend="sup">•</hi> 
               <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>as of y<hi rend="sup">•</hi> 
               <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> of y<hi rend="sup">•</hi> paſſ in &amp; tra<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>ſla<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap>o<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g> of ſeynt Thomas aforeſayd or by hymſelfe or ony other gyue ony thyn<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap> of cherytable <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 span">
                  <desc>〈…〉</desc>
               </gap> 
               <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>foreſayd .vii. yeres and .vii. <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>entes of penaunce enioyned marcyfully hath releſyd for <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 span">
                  <desc>〈…〉</desc>
               </gap>
            </p>
            <p>¶ Alſo our holy <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> Pau<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>us y<hi rend="sup">•</hi> ſeco<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>de to all tho y<hi rend="sup">•</hi> 
               <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 span">
                  <desc>〈…〉</desc>
               </gap> y<hi rend="sup">•</hi> Cha<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>ell of our lady w<hi rend="sup">t</hi> in y<hi rend="sup">t</hi> ſayd churche <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 span">
                  <desc>〈…〉</desc>
               </gap> 
               <note place="margin">
                  <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>. <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>eres and .v. <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 word">
                     <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                  </gap>.</note> was &amp; the<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> g<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>ue o<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap> 
               <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="3 letters">
                  <desc>•••</desc>
               </gap>eſſe to y<hi rend="sup">•</hi> co<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>ſer<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="3 letters">
                  <desc>•••</desc>
               </gap> 
               <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 span">
                  <desc>〈…〉</desc>
               </gap>
            </p>
            <pb facs="tcp:11820:2" rendition="simple:additions"/>
            <gap reason="duplicate" extent="1 page">
               <desc>〈1 page duplicate〉</desc>
            </gap>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
